<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tag1 on Sjmelck</title>
    <link>https://ryanbalshaw.github.io/sjmelck_pages/tags/tag1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tag1 on Sjmelck</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 15:48:07 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ryanbalshaw.github.io/sjmelck_pages/tags/tag1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Justin Smith</title>
      <link>https://ryanbalshaw.github.io/sjmelck_pages/about/justin-smith/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 15:48:07 +0200</pubDate>

      <guid>https://ryanbalshaw.github.io/sjmelck_pages/about/justin-smith/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the landing page of Justin Smith.
🐉 Who is Justin Smith? I am a post-graduate mechanical engineering student at the University of Pretoria with a passion for condition monitoring and machine learning.
💚 Fun question How can you use the ASCII values of the characters in the word &amp;ldquo;math&amp;rdquo; to get to the question posed by Ryan Balshaw?</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Time synchronous averaging and computed order tracking: Explained</title>
      <link>https://ryanbalshaw.github.io/sjmelck_pages/blog/the-tsa-and-cot-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 16:14:08 +0200</pubDate>

      <guid>https://ryanbalshaw.github.io/sjmelck_pages/blog/the-tsa-and-cot-explained/</guid>
      <description>Good day 👋
The purpose of this explanation is to detail a high-level overview of the time-synchronous average (TSA) and Computed Order Tracking (COT). This will require a basic understanding of the objectives of TSA and COT, and I will try to provide some explanations and intuition to help those who do not have a good grasp on the concepts.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Johann Bouwer</title>
      <link>https://ryanbalshaw.github.io/sjmelck_pages/about/johann-bouwer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 10:33:53 +0200</pubDate>

      <guid>https://ryanbalshaw.github.io/sjmelck_pages/about/johann-bouwer/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the landing page of Johann Bouwer.
🍜 Who is Johann Bouwer? Content loading&amp;hellip;
❤️ Fun question What do you get if you take the square root of 1764?
Click here to reveal
💡 42
graph LR;
2--&gt;sqrt3;
3--&gt;9;
3--&gt;6;
2--&gt;6;
sqrt3[&#34;sqrt(3)^2&#34;]--&gt;3;
3--&gt;3pow2[&#34;3^2&#34;];
2--&gt;3pow2;
3pow2--&gt;9;
6--&gt;???;
9--&gt;???;
</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Douw Marx</title>
      <link>https://ryanbalshaw.github.io/sjmelck_pages/about/douw-marx/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 12:36:52 +0200</pubDate>

      <guid>https://ryanbalshaw.github.io/sjmelck_pages/about/douw-marx/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the landing page of Douw Marx.
🍻 Who is Douw Marx? I am a Mechanical Engineer. I completed my Masters in Mechanical engineering (with distinction) in the field of condition monitoring. I enjoy programming, statistics and math. I am currently working on my PhD under Prof. Kostis Gryllias
at KU Leuven, Belgium.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Ryan Balshaw</title>
      <link>https://ryanbalshaw.github.io/sjmelck_pages/about/ryan-balshaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 12:36:47 +0200</pubDate>

      <guid>https://ryanbalshaw.github.io/sjmelck_pages/about/ryan-balshaw/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the landing page of Ryan Balshaw.
🐔 Who is Ryan Balshaw? Current PhD candidate in Mechanical Engineering at the University of Pretoria, my research is focused on asset condition monitoring using Artificial Intelligence. I am passionate about vibration analysis, machine learning and asset integrity, with a keen interest in signal processing and it’s applications in practice.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Pretty plotting in Python.</title>
      <link>https://ryanbalshaw.github.io/sjmelck_pages/blog/pretty-plotting-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 17:18:41 +0200</pubDate>

      <guid>https://ryanbalshaw.github.io/sjmelck_pages/blog/pretty-plotting-in-python/</guid>
      <description>How to get really nice plots Good day 👋
The purpose of this explanation is to give an example of how to get really nice plots in Python. This is still in development. At this point in time I used it as a trial post when setting up the blog. Hopefully I will fix it soon (17 April 2023).</description>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
